lifeproof.com 2019-08-08

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy (this “Policy”) applies to lifeproof.com, operated by Otter Products, LLC (“Otter”). This Policy describes how Otter collects, uses and shares the personal information you provide on otterproducts.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information, and how you can access and update this information.

We value your privacy, and we make this Policy easily accessible throughout this site to assist you in understanding how we handle your personal information. We want to make your online experience enjoyable and safe. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want you to understand fully our policies surrounding the attainment and use of that information.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at [https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request)

#### Information We Collect

You are not required to provide personal information that we request. If you choose not to provide the information we have requested, we may not be able to provide you with our products or services.

When you make a purchase from this site, request to receive our electronic newsletters, participate in our message boards or forums, write a review or provide feedback, submit a warranty claim, or participate in polls, surveys, or contests, we may collect information from you, including your name, email address, telephone number, mailing address, payment information, and social media handles. If you register to be one of our vendors or service providers, we may collect additional information about you including the company you represent and your job title. If you purchase a product or service from this site for another party, we may collect information from you about the other party, including the other party’s name and mailing address. We will only use this information for the specific purpose for which you provided it. If you believe that a third party has provided us with your personal information or you no longer wish us to possess your information, you may request deletion of your information by emailing us [privacy@lifeproof.com](mailto:privacy@lifeproof.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Please be aware that this site includes links to other sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Otter. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their respective privacy policies. We encourage you to read carefully the privacy policy of any site you visit. Similarly, some of our pages utilize framing techniques to serve content to from third parties, while preserving the look and feel of this site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to Otter.

This site includes social media features, such as the Facebook “like” button. These features may collect your IP address, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the third party providing it.

#### How We Use Your Personal Information

The personal information we collect allows us to fulfill your order or warranty claim, and provide the services you request from us. We may supplement this with information from a third-party source, such as FedEx, in order to validate delivery address so we can properly ship your order.

If you fill out a survey or form, participate in a contest or submit a testimonial on this site, and in the process, provide us with personal information, we use this information to notify contest winners and award prizes, to monitor site traffic or personalize this site, and to send participants an email newsletter. We also display on this site personal testimonials of satisfied customers and other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us using our contact information below.

We provide site users the opportunity to receive communications from us, including a periodic newsletter, product promotions, polls, surveys, and any other information that we believe may be pertinent to the user. You may opt out of receiving any, non-service related communications by emailing us at [privacy@lifeproof.com](mailto:privacy@lifeproof.com), by clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email we send to you, or by replying to any email we send you and entering the word UNSUBSCRIBE in the subject line.

This site offers a publicly accessible blog. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas might be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at the contact information below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Otter uses information voluntarily given by our users to enhance their experience on this site, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites, or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.

#### Disclosure to Third Parties

We may provide your personal information to our affiliated entities and to third parties that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or warranty claim, offering customer service, sending our communications, and administering testimonials and contests and administering our vendor and service provider programs. These third parties are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. Except as otherwise provided herein, we will not share your personal information with any other third-party organizations except with your express consent.

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required to by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal processes, and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or response to a government request.

#### Log Files, Cookies, and Other Tracking Technologies

This site utilizes industry standard analytics packages that automatically gathers limited information on site users, and stores this information in server log files. This information may include IP addresses, browser type, referring pages, operating system used, and date/time stamps. This information is used only for site administration, as well as for analysis of site usage and trends.

Otter collects user traffic usage characteristics throughout its site. However, we do not correlate this data with individual user information. Otter may analyze usage statistics according to a user’s domain name, browser type, and Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions (MIME) type by reading this information from data contained in the user’s browser.

Otter may collect and catalog search terms in its search function that users employ, but such collection and cataloging are not associated with individual users. We may use search terms to determine the areas of this site most important to users, based on the characteristics of usage or traffic of those areas. We will not use these search terms to track what any particular individual users read, but rather the performance of each page. This may help us to build a better web-based experience for you.

Otter and its affiliates and service providers (e.g., marketing providers, analytics providers, and/or payment processors) utilize technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts. Otter uses these technologies in analyzing trends, administering this site, tracking users’ movements around this site, and gathering demographic information about our site users. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these third parties on an individual as well as an aggregated basis.

We use cookies for our shopping cart, to remember users’ settings (e.g., language preference), to enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the overall experience of using this site, and to authenticate users. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use this site, but your ability to use some features or areas of this site, such as our blogs, polls, and surveys, may be limited.

We utilize a third-party service provider to understand better our site users’ needs and to optimize this service and experience. This technology helps us to understand better our users’ experience and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. This third-party service provider uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on your behavior and your devices (in particular device’s IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), and preferred language used to display our website). This third-party service provider stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither the third-party service provider nor we will use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. You can opt-out to the third-party service provider’s storing of data about your usage of our site and third-party service provider use of tracking cookies on other websites by enabling the Do Not Track header in your browser.

We utilize a third-party service provider to manage our advertising on other sites. This service provider may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites, in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish not to have this information used for serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union by clicking [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

We use “local storage”, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties that provide certain features on this site (e.g., YouTube) also use local storage, and HTML5, to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

#### Access to Personal Information

If you would like to know whether we hold any of your personal information, you may request this information by emailing us at [privacy@lifeproof.com](mailto:privacy@lifeproof.com).

If your personally identifiable information changes, you may update it by logging into your online account or by emailing us at [privacy@lifeproof.com](mailto:privacy@lifeproof.com). If you no longer wish us to possess your information, you may request deletion of your information by emailing us at [privacy@lifeproof.com](mailto:privacy@lifeproof.com). You also may make your request by telephone or by postal mail at the address/phone number indicated in the contact information below. We will respond to your request within thirty (30) days. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Protection of Personal Information

We follow accepted industry standards to protect any personal information you have provided to us. However, please be aware that no method of electronic transmission or storage can ever be fully secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee the absolute security of your information.

Nevertheless, the security of your personal information is extremely important to us. For instance, we employ various firewalls and other security tactics to keep your information secure. We do not store your complete credit card information on our internal web server. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using transport layer security (TLS) technology. While there is risk inherent in every Internet transaction, be assured that we are work hard to ensure that risk is minimal.

#### International Users

Otter is a United States-based company. All the information you provide will be transferred to the United States. Otter complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield framework and the U.S. – Swiss Privacy Shield framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland.

#### EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield

Otter participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Otter is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and the United Kingdom and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Frameworks, and to view our certification, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List. [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/list>]

Otter is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Otter complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, the United Kingdom and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, Otter is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Otter may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Privacy Shield website [<https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint>], you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

#### Changes to This Policy

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Otter. If we make any material changes, we will notify you by email or by means of a notice on this Site or by an email to your address on file prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to review periodically this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

#### Contact Details

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Policy, or you wish to contact us by postal mail, our contact information is as follows:

Otter Products, LLC  
ATTN: Privacy  
209 South Meldrum Street  
Fort Collins, CO 80521  
Phone: 1-855-688-7269  
Email: [privacy@lifeproof.com](mailto:privacy@lifeproof.com)

This Policy was last updated on March 13, 2019.
